Nobody enjoys fighting through a dense
form.
Small fields, repeated questions, and
visual clutter turn simple tasks into
work—and can create real barriers for
blind and low-vision users.
VocaForm replaces that friction with one
guided voice conversation.
Upload, listen, answer naturally,
review, and download—with screen-reader
structure, keyboard control, high
contrast, and 200% text
reflow built in.
VocaForm can start from either an
uploaded document or a public Google or
Microsoft responder link.
Here I choose a synthetic medical intake
PDF.
GPT-5.6 Sol
identifies every question and
requirement, while evidence checks block
unsupported fields before the interview
begins.
Now OpenAI Realtime guides the same
medical interview by voice.
VocaForm: What brings you in today?
VocaForm: Just a brief description of
your main reason for the visit.
User: Recurring headaches.
VocaForm: Thanks. Let me record that,
and then we'll keep going.
VocaForm: Saved.
Every write passes through versioned
application tools.
Code—not the model—decides what is
stored, and the keyboard path remains
equal.
Before export, VocaForm catches one
missing required answer.
I correct it inline, then GPT-5.6 Sol
runs a separate, non-mutating
semantic review.
It can flag ambiguity or contradiction,
but cannot rewrite the user's answers.
The result: eight of eight fields placed
in a copied PDF, with the source
unchanged.
Now the second form reveals the other
aha moment.
The Memory Vault suggests only three
contact details I explicitly approved.
Nothing is reused until I confirm it.
Medical answers are excluded, and every
remembered item can be corrected or
forgotten.
Public Google and Microsoft Forms use
the same trusted journey: read-only
inspection, voice or text interview, and
fresh consent before supported answers
are prepared in an isolated provider
page.
VocaForm verifies every control again,
then stops before Submit.
The final click stays with the user.
Codex became my build partner.
I used it to research APIs, rebuild my
prototype in modular TypeScript, and
test browser and accessibility
flows—even continuing remotely from my
phone.
Inside VocaForm, I used GPT-5.6 Sol
to compile unfamiliar forms
and run a separate semantic
review.
Together, they gave me speed without
giving up human control.
VocaForm.
One form.
One conversation.
Done.